Guide to the New-York Historical Society Schenectady Collection 1688?-1883, undated (bulk, 1710s-1840s) MS 544
New-York Historical Society
New-York Historical Society Schenectady collection
1688?-1883, undated (bulk, 1710s-1840s)
New-York Historical Society
MS 544
0.63 Linear feet in two document boxes
Deeds, indentures, surveys, leases, patents, charters, tax lists, receipts, promissory notes, warrants, accounts, petitions of early subscribers and city residents, memoranda, bills, charters, military orders, receipts, and commissions; acts; election records; summons; official correspondence; minutes of meetings of residents and local officials; and various other public and private documents, 1688-1883 (bulk 1710-1840), pertaining to the city and residents of Schenectady, New York.
Arrangement Note
The collection is arranged in two boxes. The first box advances in rough chronological order. The second box includes mostly undated documents, along with a few folders of material with date ranges that did not fit cleanly into the chronological sequence of box 1. The container list below attempts to smooth the chronological presentation of these files but some box 2 folders of dated material will be found at the end of the box 1 chronological sequence. Also, undated documents found with dated documents in box 1 were left in place.
Access Restrictions
Open to qualified researchers.
Immediate Source of Acquisition Note
To be determined.
Scope and Contents Note
Deeds, indentures, surveys, leases, patents, charters, tax lists, receipts, promissory notes, warrants, accounts, petitions of early subscribers and city residents, memoranda, bills, charters, military orders, receipts, and commissions; acts; election records; summons; official correspondence; minutes of meetings of residents and local officials; and various other public and private documents, 1688-1883 (bulk 1710s-1840s), pertaining to the city and residents of Schenectady, New York.
Several early documents concern local government and government officials, elections, etc., as well as the provisioning of the colonial army and military defense of Schenectady during the French and Indian War; land transfers, ownership, and land use, including the division and sale of common lands; and the organization, funding, and administration of churches, schools, and local militia.
Individual documents include a tax list of residents, 1737-1738; drafts of charters for the Borough Town of Schenectady, 1765 and 1768; statement of election of yearly officers, 1749; will of Adam Einick, Jan. 29, 1770; an agreement between Abraham Dudly and Ebenezer Belknap relative to a patent steam engine designed by Junia Curtis, Sep. 6, 1816; lists of residents and local officials for various years; letters to Gen. Richard Dodge of Johnstown, Montgomery County, 1820-1829, from the Mohawk Bank of Schenectady; 70 summons signed by H. R. Wendell; reports of the trustees of school district 1, 3rd and 4th wards, 1847 and 1848; various legal and financial papers related to Schenectady ferries and ferry service; and several depositions, bonds, receipts, contracts, letters, estate papers, powers of attorney, warrants, etc. recording the commercial and legal affairs of city residents during the eighteenth and early nineteenth century.
Included are several documents pertaining to members of the Van Eps, Sanders, Glen, Schuyler, Brat (Bradt), Vrooman, Groot, Empie, Mynderse, Wendell, and other early families of Schenectady, New York, and vicinity.
Church buildings -- New York (State) -- Schenectady.; Commons -- New York (State) -- Schenectady.; Elections -- New York (State) -- Schenectady.; Ferries -- Law and legislation -- New York (State) -- Schenectady.; Justices of the peace.; Land tenure -- New York (State) -- Schenectady.; Land titles -- New York (State) -- Schenectady.; Local government -- New York (State) -- Schenectady.; Public lands -- New York (State) -- Schenectady.; Schools -- New York (State) -- Schenectady.; Taxation -- New York (State) -- Schenectady.; New York (State) -- History -- French and Indian War, 1755-1763.; Schenectady (N.Y.) -- Appropriations and expenditures.; Schenectady (N.Y.) -- Church history.; Schenectady (N.Y.) -- History -- 18th century.; Schenectady (N.Y.) -- Politics and government -- 18th century.; Accounts.; Bonds (legal records).; Charters.; Contracts.; Deeds.; Depositions.; Indentures.; Lists (document genres); Orders (military records).; Petitions.; Promissory notes.; Receipts (financial records); Summonses.; Dodge, Richard, 1762-1832; Bratt family; De Groot family; Empie family; Glen family; Mynderse family; Saunders family; Schuyler family; Van Epps family; Vrooman family; Wendel family; Mohawk Bank (Schenectady, N.Y.); New York (State). Militia
- Extracts out of Minutes, 1688(?) September 17 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  Scope and Contents
  Petition and Request by Teunice regarding corn mill. Ludovicas Cobes is clerk of the court.
- Conveyance of Lot, 1702 March 30 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  Conveyance of lot of ground to Simon Groot from Royer Schermerhorn, Jan Baptist Van Eps, Jan Wemp.
- Bond, 1707 August 30 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  Johannes Sanderse Glen bound to Helena Glenn for 120 pounds.
- Order to Relieve, 1711 August 13 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  Order to relieve the detachment of regular corps; keep strict guard. Order sent by Ro Hunter to Captain John Sanderse Glen.
- Order to Repair Forts at Schenectady and Albany, 1711 October 10 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  General Assembly voted sum of money to repair forts at Albany and Schenectady; order to repair sent by Ro Hunter to Captain John Sanderse Glen.
- Confirmation of Township, 1714 November 6 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  Confirmation of Township of Schenectady requested by Thomas Dongan, Lt. Governor of New York, and granted by King George.
- Indenture of Release, 1717 May 29 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  Indenture of Release from Patentees of Schenectady (Hendrick Vroman, Ryert Schermerhorne, John Wemp, Johannis Geller, Aerent Bratt) to Volkert Symonson, Garret Von Brachell, John Barense Wemp and Hendrick Vroman.
- Promise to pay, 1718 June 18 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  Promise to pay 18 shillings by Junder Witting to Evert Wendl.
- Bill, 1718 August 10 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  Bill (Dutch) for 12 shillings against Charles Hause by Rodser Flyt.
- Conveyance, 1722 October 9 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  Conveyance of lot for 200 pounds from Daniel Ketelhuyn to Stephanis Groesbeck.
- Account, 1725-1728 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  Account of Mr. Jacob Glenn, signed by William Peters.
- Indenture, 1727 December 1 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  Indenture between Cornelis Van Alstyn and wife (Marte) and Aerent Bratt and wife (Janetie) for tract of land.
- Conveyance, 1727/8 February 20 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  Conveyance from Cornelis Van der Volgen to Tunnus Van der Volgen of meadow land.
- Bond, 1727/8 March 8 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  Lowerens Van der Volgen, Gerret Gybess van Brachell, Dierik Groot, Arenot Dgray bound unto Tunnus Van der Volgen for the sum of 420 pounds.
- Appointment, 1727/8 March 22 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  Appointment of Simon Vroman and Jacob Geler to serve for Nether Dutch Reformed Church signed by Arent Danielse, Nicholas Schuyler, Cornelius Van der Volege Wilhelmus.
- Receipt, 1728 September (Box 1, Folder 3)
  Receipt from Caleb Beck for 10 pounds to Evert Wendell, Esq. and Harris Wendell.
- Account, 1728 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  Account of Mr. Jacob Glen for Sept. - Nov. 1728, signed by Andrew Teller.
- Promise to Pay(?), 1729 May 6 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  Appears to be in Dutch and likely a promise to pay signed by Nicholas Schuyler.
- Release, 1729 July 10 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  Jan Wemp release to Evert Van Eps.
- Bill, 1729 August 20 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  Bill for transport rendered to William Dieters by Johann Mynderse.
- Promise to pay, 1729 December 5 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  Promise to pay 30 shillings to Evert Windoh by Joseph Brohon.
- Promise to pay, 1730s? (Box 1, Folder 4)
  Promise to pay James Ahyander 11 pounds signed by Jacob Glen and Arent Bradt.
- Transport, 1730 August 14 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  Transport from Akis Braat to Albert Vedder certain lot of land and brewhouse.
- Warrant, 1732 May 5 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  Warrant against Jan Baptist Von Eps signed by Ahasueras Wendell.
- Land Papers, 1733-1748, 1770s? (Box 1, Folder 5)
  Documents are in Dutch. Includes field notes, draft replies regarding actions of the Dutch Church at Schenectady, invoices, receipts, plans, and sketches. Most are in the autograph of Jacob Glen. Plats of land include that between Philip Livingston, Nicholas Schuyler, deFort Street, and de Brounery Street; and one regarding land near dePeyster and Van Slyck. Also includes part of a letter in which mention is made of General Washington and Van Eps vendue in the autograph of Jacob Glen.
- Military Commissions, 1733-1751 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  Dates for Military Commissions for many Schenectady inhabits from 1733-1751
- Bond, 1733 May 22 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  Gerhardt Erickson bound to John Miln for 20 pounds.
- Protest, 1733 August 24 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  Document (Dutch?), according to accompanying note, is a protest against the excommunication of member of Dutch Church.
- Indenture, 1734 September 11 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  Indenture of Release between Jacobus Van Slyck and Sander Van Eps regarding yearly rent of Merchantable Deal Board (Measure of standing trees).
- Power to Attorney, 1734 December 20 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  William Stoddard's (of Boston) Power of Attorney granted to Evert Wendell, especially in matters dealing with James Donaldson.
- Request, 1734/5 March 24 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  Request to rent pasture for summer by James Donaldson to Evert Ivendall.
- Indenture, 1736 September 6 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  Grant of Lowlands from Harman Vidder and wife, Margriet to John Collins and wife, Margriet.
- Receipt, 1736 September 6 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  Receipt for shipped animal skins to Robert Livingston signed by Peter Groenendyck.
- Invoice, 1737 February 10 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  John Empie's account bought of Alexander Alexander.
- Petition, 1737 October 13 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  A petition was presented to the Councilhold at Fort George that Capt. Philip Schulyer purchased woodland from Native Indians, which was injurous to inhabitants of Schenectady because woodland supplies firewood.
- Receipt, 1737 November 25 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  Promise to repay Jacob Glen signed by Gerrit Lansingh.
- Receipt, 1737 November 30 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  Receipt to Dr. Nather signed by John Wendell.
- Tax List, 1737-1738 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  Includes original manuscript list of 252 tax payers of Schenectady for years 1737-1738. Consists of a list of names with a figure opposite each name, presumably the amount of tax levied.
- Document with seal, 1738 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  Document (Dutch ?) notes Arent Brat, Abraham Meebie, Jacob Glen, Sander Lansingh -- may involve court case
- Indenture, 1738/9 January 9 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  Indenture from Arent Brat and Jan Wemp to Barent Wemp and Andries Brat regarding yearly rent of Merchantable Deal Board (Measure of standing trees).
- Obligation, 1738/9 February 21 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  Obligation of performance from Arent Brat and Jacob Glen to Sander Lansingh, Albert Vedder, Isaac Truex, Jacob Vrooman, Johan A. Vedder, Jacob Schermerhorn, and Harmen van Antwerpen.
- Bond, 1740 June 3 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  Garrit Van Brahil bound to John Baptiste Van Eps for 400 pounds.
- Receipt, 1740 June 4 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  Receipt (Dutch?) to Joseph Mynders from John Wies.
- Order, 1740 June 21 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  Jeremiah Swart is determined to be father of daughter Elizabeth born to unwed mother, Claertie Marienus, and ordered to pay support.
- Deed(?), 1740 July (Box 1, Folder 3)
  Document, with seal, appears to be in Dutch. Signatories Albert Veder, ___ Truers, Pymer Vrooman, Cornelie Van Dyck, Jacob Pchevnerhooven, Johannis Vedder.
- Letter, 1740 July 5 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  Letter (Dutch?) to Hendrick Van Renselar from John Visger.
- Receipt, 1740 November 5 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  Related Materials
  Receipt (Dutch?) to Adam Emgie signed Johannis Myne.
- Release, 1741 April 20 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  Release from Johannis E. Van Eps to Abraham Van Eps.
- Receipt, 1741 October 29 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  Original document appears to be Dutch. Translation: "Received of John Sanders 9 and twenty shillings for account of Piet Cock, the negro, for one saddle furnished by Cock to Sanders." Signed by Reyier Schermerhorn.
- Indenture of Release, 1743 January (Box 1, Folder 4)
  Indenture from Jacob Glen to Harmen and Cornelius Groot regarding yearly rent of Merchantable Deal Board (Measure of standing trees).
- Receipt, 1743 September 7 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  Receipt (Dutch?) signed by Johannak Cock mention of John Sanders.
- Convenant, 1743 October 12 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  Convenant to divide land among Johan Van Eps, John B. Van Eps, and Abraham Van Eps.
- Release, 1745 March 13 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  Release for certain lot of land from John Wemp and Arent Bradt to Joseph Yates.
- Indenture, 1745 August 7 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  Indenture from Albert Vedder to Alexander Vedder (son) conveying house, lot, and brewhouse.
- Indenture, 1745 August 7 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  Indenture from Albert Vedder to Arent Alb. Vedder (son) conveying lot of woodland.
- Statement, 1746 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  Series of signed statement regarding Jacob Glen. (Dutch?) Signed by Abraham Marseles, James Goet, Robert Hagendorn, Jacob Crasteyange, Abraham Crasteyange, John Hyde, Johanis Bradt, John Meebie, Johannis Van Eps, Gerrit Wendell, Nico Casdegras, Gelles Van Vorst, Gerrit A. Lansingh, and Thomas Bancker.
- Note, 1746 August (Box 1, Folder 4)
  Pay to Gerrit A. Lansingh all wages signed by Jemee Marenet (?).
- Receipt, 1747 October 22 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  Receipt (Dutch?) signed by Cornelius Groot, Sly Groot, and Peter Van Bracken.
- Letter, 1747 December (Box 1, Folder 4)
  Letter (Dutch?) to Jan Wemp from Johannis A. Vedder, Peter Groendyck, Cornelius Van Slyk, John Sanders, Gerrit A. Lansingh, and Gerrit Van Antwerpen.
- Sworn Testimony, 1747/8 March 6 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  Ahasueras Marseles was with Sandney Trueset
- Receipt, 1748/9 January 12 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  Receipt -- Jacob Glen and Arent Brat are to pay to John Sanders, signed Elias Post.
- Election of the Yearly Officers of the Township of Schenectady, 1749 April (Box 1, Folder 4)
  Appears to have recorded for whom voting citizens of Schenectady voted for various official positions.
- List of Names, undated (Box 1, Folder 7)
  Long list of names, some crossed out.
- Act, 1750 (Box 2, Folder 2)
  Act to build second road to Albany, township of Schenectady
- Indenture of Release, 1750 March 28 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  Indenture regarding yearly rent from Arent Bratt to Alexander Lansingh and Adam Van Slyck.
- Release for rent, 1750 December 17 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  Release from Arent Bradt for rent to the minister, elders, and deacons of the Reformed Protestant Dutch Church of Schenectady.
- Invoice, 1752 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  "Samuel Steers has worked for 7 days..." for First Berricks.
- Memorandum (Dutch), 1752 February 10 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  Memorandum has long list of names.
- Note (Dutch), 1753 March 27 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  Note between Jan Wempel/Efrem Wempel and Robert Sanders
- Receipt, 1753 June 20 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  Receipt for animal skins signed by Nicholas Schuyler to Johan Christman.
- Invoice, 1755 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  Invoice for building barracks directed to Major General Shirley.
- Receipt, 1755 June 16 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  John Wempel to pay John Sanders five pounds for steerman to Oswego
- Order, 1755 August 12 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  Order by James Delaney (Delancey?) to Lt. Col. Jacob Glen (of the Schenectady Battalion) to dispatch men to do duty in Majesty's Fort in Schenectady.
- Receipt, 1755 September 8 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  Jacob Van Schajck to pay Abraham Yates four pounds for Batoe pressed.
- Receipt, 1755 November (Box 1, Folder 7)
  Note between Adam Emgie and Jacob Glen.
- Receipt, 1755 November (Box 1, Folder 7)
  Receipt to First Berricks, account of Sybrant Van Schaick.
- Invoice, 1756 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  Invoice by Christopher Yates to Col. Glen.
- Invoice, 1756 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  Invoice for taking care of King's horses directed to Jacob Glen signed by Johan Hall
- Receipt, 1756 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  Receipt given Col. Jacob Glen by William De Graff for payment of boards to ye use of ye barks.
- Receipt, 1756 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  Receipt signed by Abram Groot directed to Gerritt A. Lansingh.
- Memorandum, 1756 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  Memorandum of money given to Robert Sanders by Jacob Glen to pay the barracks.
- Receipt, 1756 April 9 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  Receipt to Capt. George Wilmott signed by John Cowley.
- Receipt, 1756 May 11 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  Receipt for hickory for ye barracks signed by Harmen Van Slyck.
- Sworn Statement, 1756 July 16 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  Sworn statement regarding wood delivery by Jacob Followider sworn before Jan B. Van Eps, Justice.
- Receipt, 1756 July 30 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  Receipt with affadavit attached by Peter Onderkeck in payment for 46 lodewood delivered to the bercks and blockhouses. Directed to John Sanders.
- Sworn Statement, 1756 August 9 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  Sworn Statement regarding wood delivery by Isaac Vedder sworn before Hans Hansen, Mayor of Albany.
- Sworn Statement, 1757 April 30 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  Sworn statement by Frederik Cloudt sworn before Jan B. Van Eps, Justice.
- Bond, 1757 September 16 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  Promise to pay by John Christofell Hotte to Col. Jacob Glen. John Sanders, witness.
- Bond, 1757 September 17 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  Promise to pay by Jandnik Zaib (?) to Col. Jacob Glen. John Sanders, witness.
- Bond, 1757 September 17 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  Promise to pay by William Bath to Col. Jacob Glen. John Sanders, witness.
- Bond, 1757 September 17 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  Promise to pay to Col. Jacob Glen by Sammy Cave. John Sanders, witness.
- Bond, 1757 October 18 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  Bond to do Military Duty signed by Hendrick Brower directed to Col. Jacob Glen. John Sanders, witness.
- Promise to Pay, 1757 December 1 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  Promise to pay Jacob Glen 23 pounds; promise to pay John Sanders 2 pounds by Barent Hend Wempel.
- Bill (Dutch), 1758 October (Box 1, Folder 7)
  Bill of the Church Warnders (Wardens)
- Receipt, 1758-1759 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  Receipt to John Callender to Joseph Tyler.
- Plea, 1759 February 21 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  Plea for 3 pounds each for fetching and loading artillery stores directed to Jacob Van Slyck and Jan B. Van Eps. 23 subscribers.
- Receipt, 1759 November 6 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  Receipt for Military Service directed to Captain Richard Reas for money received by Lt. Bates' Company.
- List of Names, undated (Box 1, Folder 8)
  List of 26 names with numbers opposite.
- List of Names, undated (Box 1, Folder 8)
  List of 30 names with numbers opposite.
- List of Names, undated (Box 1, Folder 8)
  List of almost 50 names with numbers.
- Invoice, 1761-1762 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  Mr. Jelles Douw Van Vorst to the Estate of Jacob Glen.
- Conveyance, 1762 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  Conveyance of woodland from Col. Jacob Glen to John Sanders.
- Note, 1763 August 13 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  Note regarding being "down" next week by Stephen Darby.
- Invoice, 1764 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  John Emplie's account with Duncan Phyn & Ellice
- Account, 1764 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  Account of Adam Embyen by Philip Hemming.
- Draft Charter for Schenectady, 1765 February 9 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  Draft from the Attorney General, J.T. Kempe to the Council Board.
- Assignment, 1765 February 19 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  Assignment of pay in militia to Joseph Chaphin signed by John Bratham. John Woller, witness.
- Bond, 1765 October 14 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  Stephen Dudley bound to John Lansingh for 71 pounds.
- Note, 1767 February 2 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  Note from Jason Hospard to Peter Tagert about New York Currency.
- List of Elected Officials, 1767 September (Box 1, Folder 8)
  List of Officers to be in Schenectady Charter.
- Promise to Pay, 1767 September 17 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  Promise by Robert Hagedorn to pay Jacob Glen 6 pounds.
- Account (Dutch), 1768-1770 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  Account of John Empie.
- Request, 1768 October 26 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  Request to supply from Henry Van Driessenzy to Hendrick Glen.
- Letter, 1769 June 24 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  Letter regarding bill to the Honorable Mr. Penn from Cupane.
- Note, 1769 July 17 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  Note by John Deygert requesting 8-10 pounds to be repaid directed to John Sanders.
- Invoice, 1769 December (Box 1, Folder 8)
  Invoice from Mr. Packer to Paschal N. Smith.
- Draft Charter, 1765 October 15 (Box 1, Folder 9)
  Draft Charter for Schenectady referred to Committee.
- Draft Charter, 1768 (Box 1, Folder 9)
  Draft Charter for Schenectady.
- Last Will and Testament, 1770 January 29 (Box 1, Folder 10)
  Last Will and Testament of Adam Einick (Emick?).
- Advertisement, 1770 March 27 (Box 1, Folder 10)
  Advertisment warning all persons not to cut, etc wood from land belonging to late Adam Empie by John Empie.
- Promissory Note, 1770 October 16 (Box 1, Folder 10)
  Promise to pay William Hanna for value received as witness by John Empie.
- Account, 1771-1774 (Box 1, Folder 10)
  Account of John Thurman to John Empie.
- Receipt, 1771 November 18 (Box 1, Folder 10)
  Receipt to John Empie from Royner Mynderse.
- Promissory Note, 1772 March 17 (Box 1, Folder 10)
  Promise to pay Charles Morrison as value received as witness by John Empie.
- Bond (copy), 1772 September 28 (Box 1, Folder 10)
  Copy of Bond stating that J. Christopher Pearson is indebted to John Duncan for 13 pounds, 15 shillings.
- Deed, 1772 December 23 (Box 1, Folder 10)
  Parcel of woodland lying 4 miles eastward of Schenectady between Minister Elders and Deacons of the Reformed Protestant Dutch Church and John Glen.
- Account, 1773 (Box 1, Folder 10)
  Account of Robeson & Martin to John Empie.
- Invoice, 1773 April 10 (Box 1, Folder 10)
  Invoice to Major Sherritt from Phyn & Ellice.
- Receipt, 1773 April 13 (Box 1, Folder 10)
  Receipt for storage of Majesty's ordnance stores between John Graham, Sgt. of artillery, and Phyn & Ellis.
- Letter, 1773 June 18 (Box 1, Folder 10)
  Letter about shipped goods to Major Shirritt from Phyn & Ellice.
- Invoice, 1773 July 7 (Box 1, Folder 10)
  Invoice of Major Sherritt to Phyn & Ellice.
- Injunction in Court of Chancery (copy), 1774 August 19 (Box 1, Folder 10)
  Injunction against James Jackson and John and Deborah Sanders by Reyer Schermerhorn.
- Invoice, 1775-1776 (Box 1, Folder 10)
  Invoice to Adam Condey from John Sanders.
- Receipt, 1775 August 24 (Box 1, Folder 10)
  Receipt received from John Sanders signed by Cornelius de Graaf.
- Invoice (Dutch), 1776 February 3 (Box 1, Folder 10)
  Tobyas Ten Eyck's invoice against John Sanders.
- Note, 1776 August 11 (Box 1, Folder 10)
  Joseph Peeke has signed the General Association recommended by the Honorable Continental Congress.
- Account, 1777-1779 (Box 1, Folder 10)
  Account page with autograph of John Sanders.
- Account, 1777-1883 (Box 1, Folder 10)
  Account of Alida Vroman to John Empie.
- Receipt, 1777 April 2 (Box 1, Folder 10)
  Receipt received from John Empie signed David Fairchild.
- Letter, 1777 August 21 (Box 1, Folder 10)
  Receipt of letter; will lay proposals before you. Letter to John Sanders from Royner Mynderse, Chairman of Committee Chamber.
- Indenture, 1777 September 19 (Box 1, Folder 10)
  Mathais Weigertin bound to S. Ten Eyck for 4 years.
- Account, 1779-1782 (Box 1, Folder 10)
  Account of John Roseboom to John Empie.
- Receipt, 1779 September 28 (Box 1, Folder 10)
  Receipt from Zeger Van Santvoord to Vroman.
- Note, 1779 November 25 (Box 1, Folder 10)
  Note regarding borrowed use of "Smith Bellos" from Benjamin and John Young to John Empie.
- Articles of Agreement, 1780 (Box 2, Folder 3)